<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tarek RAISSI</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tarek RAISSI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-FR</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015, Tarek Raissi; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encadrement doctoral</title>
      <link>/phd/students</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phd/students</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;encadrement-doctoral:de354e522e3337061ca4d76bfdd32d47&#34;&gt;Encadrement doctoral&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaétan Videau&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre : Méthodes garanties pour l’estimation d’état et le contrôle de cohérence des
systèmes non linéaires à temps continu. &lt;em&gt;Thèse soutenue le 17 juillet 2009&lt;/em&gt;. Durée 33.5 mois.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ramatou Seydou&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre : Contribution au développement des techniques ensemblistes pour l’estimation de l’état et des entrées des systèmes à temps continu: application à la détection de défauts. &lt;em&gt;Thèse soutenue le 3 d´ecembre 2012&lt;/em&gt;. Durée 34 mois&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rihab El Houda Thabet&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre: Surveillance Préventive des Systèmes à Incertitudes Bornées. &lt;em&gt;Thèse soutenue le 9 décembre 2014&lt;/em&gt;. Durée 35 mois&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakhdar Aggoune&lt;/strong&gt;. Title: Développement de méthodes de diagnostic à base d’une approche paramétrique pour des systèmes industriels. &lt;em&gt;Soutenance prévue en septembre 2015&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basma Yousfi&lt;/strong&gt;. Title: Contribution à l’observation et au pronostic des systèmes incertains. &lt;em&gt;Soutenance prévue en décembre 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rihab Lamouchi&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre : Commande Tolérante aux Fautes à base d’observateurs intervalles. &lt;em&gt;Thèse débutée en janvier 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;master-recherche:de354e522e3337061ca4d76bfdd32d47&#34;&gt;Master Recherche&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asma Ben Rejab&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre : Observation robuste pour des systèmes à dérivation non entière, &lt;em&gt;Mars - Juillet 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghazi BEL HAJ FREJ&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre: Etude de la diagnosticabilité des systèmes à évènements discrets. &lt;em&gt;Fev. 2012 - Sept. 2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Pascal COBUT&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre: Méthodes ensemblistes dédiées au diagnostic. &lt;em&gt;Fev. 2009 - Juin 2009&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Pierre BRIDIER&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre: Méthodes garanties pour le diagnostic des systèmes qLPV Application à la détection de pannes oscillatoires d’un A380. &lt;em&gt;Fev. 2008 - Sep. 2008&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damien REYNAUD&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre: Estimation d’état pour des systèmes non linéaires incertains. Application au diagnostic. &lt;em&gt;Fev. 2007 - Juin 2007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaétan VIDEAU&lt;/strong&gt;. Titre: Méthodes ensemblistes pour le diagnostic. &lt;em&gt;Fev. 2006 - Juin 2006&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Présentations aux Groupes de Travail du GDR MACS</title>
      <link>/publications/gdr</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/gdr</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;présentations-aux-groupes-de-travail-du-gdr-macs:f50d9a460e371e63215327570bb45ee7&#34;&gt;Présentations aux Groupes de Travail du GDR MACS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, D. Efimov, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Stabilisation robuste d’une classe de systèmes non linéaires incertains&lt;/em&gt;,
Groupe de Travail Méthodes et Outils pour la Synthèse et l’Analyse en Robustesse (MOSAR), 24-11-2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;F. Khemane, R. Malti, M. Thomassin, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Identification fréquentielle par modèle non entier
utilisant une approche ensembliste&lt;/em&gt;, Groupe de Travail Identification, 27-11-2008, Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Videau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Contrôle d&amp;rsquo;intégrité paramétrique par satisfaction de contraintes
: cas des systèmes non linéaires à temps continu&lt;/em&gt;, Groupe de Travail Sûreté, Surveillance, Supervision
(S3), 30-05-2008, Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Complex interval arithmetic using polar form&lt;/em&gt;, Groupe de travail Méthodes Ensemblistes
pour l&amp;rsquo;Automatique (GT MEA), 03-02-2005, Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Intégration numérique garantie de systèmes décrits par des équations algébro-différentielles
non linéaires. Application à l’estimation garantie d’état et de paramètres dans un contexte à erreurs
bornées&lt;/em&gt;, Groupe de Travail Identification, 26-09-2002, Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;revues-internationales:480c4de99851329b51acecc000e2e84f&#34;&gt;Revues internationales&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;S. Chebotarev, D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, Interval Observers for Continuous-Time LPV
Systems with L1/L∞ performance, &lt;em&gt;Automatica&lt;/em&gt;, 57(7), 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R.H. Thabet, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, C. Combastel, D. Efimov, A. Zolghadri, An effective method to interval
observer design for time-varying systems, &lt;em&gt;Automatica&lt;/em&gt;, 50(10), 2677-2684, 2014&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;H. Rios, D. Efimov, J. Davila, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, L. Fridman, and A. Zolghadri, Robust State Estimation
and Fault Detection and Identification for Linear Switched Systems, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Adaptive
Control and Signal Processing&lt;/em&gt;, 28(12), 1372-1397, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, Set Adaptive Observers for LPV Systems: Application to Fault
Detection, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Dynamic Systems, Measurement and Control&lt;/em&gt;, 136(2), 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, W. Perruquetti, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, On Interval Observers for Time-Varying DiscreteTime
Systems, &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control&lt;/em&gt;, 58(12), Pages 3218 - 3224, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, Control of nonlinear and LPV systems: interval observer-based
framework, &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control&lt;/em&gt;, 58(3), 2013. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 1.952&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Stanislav Chebotarev, A. Zolghadri, Interval State Observer for Nonlinear Time
Varying Systems, &lt;em&gt;Automatica&lt;/em&gt;, 49(1), Pages 200-205, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;S. Ramatou, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, D. Efimov, Actuator fault detection and diagnosis for flat systems:
A constraint satisfaction technique, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Applied Mathematics &amp;amp; Computer
Science&lt;/em&gt;, 23(1), 2013. (Impact factor 2010: 0.794).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, L. Fridman, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, R. Seydou, A. Zolghadri, Interval Estimation for LPV Systems
Applying High Order Sliding Mode Techniques, &lt;em&gt;Automatica&lt;/em&gt;, 48(9), 2365-2371, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, Stabilisation robuste d’une classe de systèmes non linéaires incertains,
&lt;em&gt;Journal Européen des Systèmes Automatisés&lt;/em&gt;, 46(4-5), 335-348, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, D. Efimov, A. Zolghadri, Interval state estimation for a class of nonlinear systems, &lt;em&gt;IEEE
Transactions on Automatic Control&lt;/em&gt;, 57(1), 260-265, 2012. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 1.952&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;F. Khemane, R. Malti, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, and X. Moreau, Robust estimation of fractional models in the
frequency domain using set membership methods, &lt;em&gt;Signal Processing&lt;/em&gt;, 92(7), 1591-1601, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, A. Zolghadri, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Actuators Fault Detection and Compensation under Feedback
Control, &lt;em&gt;Automatica&lt;/em&gt;, 47(8): 1699-1705, 2011. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 2.172&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Reliable amplitude and frequency estimation for biased and noisy signals, &lt;em&gt;Communications
in Nonlinear Science and Numerical Simulation&lt;/em&gt;, 16(11): 4153-4157, 2011. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 2.698&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, G. Videau, A. Zolghadri, Interval observers design for consistency checks of nonlinear
continuous-time systems, &lt;em&gt;Automatica&lt;/em&gt;, 46(3): 518-527, 2010. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 2.172&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R. Malti, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, M. Thomassin, F. Khemane, Set membership parameter estimation of fractional
models based on bounded frequency domain data, &lt;em&gt;Communications in Nonlinear Science and Numerical
Simulation&lt;/em&gt;, 15(4), 927-938, 2010. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 2.698&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, Set membership parameter estimation in the frequency domain,
International Journal of Control, &lt;em&gt;Automation, and Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 7(5), 2009. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 0.853&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Y. Candau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, L. Ibos, Complex interval arithmetic using polar form, &lt;em&gt;Reliable
Computing&lt;/em&gt;, 12(1) : 1-20, 2006. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2009: 0.68&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, Bounded error moving horizon state estimator for non-linear
continuous-time systems: application to a bioprocess system, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Process Control&lt;/em&gt;, 12(5) : 537-
545, 2005. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor 2010: 1.655&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, L. Ibos, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, Analyse de spectres de relaxation diélectrique par inversion
ensembliste: une première approche, &lt;em&gt;Revue Internationale de Génie Electrique&lt;/em&gt;, Numéro spécial, 8(1):
97-117, 2005.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, Set membership state and parameter estimation for systems
described by non-linear differential equations, &lt;em&gt;Automatica&lt;/em&gt;, 40(10): 1771-1777, 2004. (&lt;span class=&#34;blue&#34;&gt;Impact factor
2010: 2.172&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapitre-d-ouvrage-collectif:480c4de99851329b51acecc000e2e84f&#34;&gt;Chapitre d’ouvrage collectif&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, Robust State and Parameter Estimation for Nonlinear ContinuousTime
Systems in a Set-Membership Context, Modeling, Design, and Simulation of Systems with Uncertainties,
&lt;em&gt;Springer&lt;/em&gt;, 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conférences internationales</title>
      <link>/publications/conf</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/conf</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;articles-invités:b12bb71970583c53de3daa7003b0cb29&#34;&gt;Articles invités&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;B. Yousfi, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, M. Amairi and M. Aoun, &lt;em&gt;Set-membership methodology for model-based systems
prognosis&lt;/em&gt;, 9th IFAC Symposium on Fault Detection, Supervision and Safety of Technical Processes
(SafeProcess 2015), September 2-4, 2015, Paris, France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, W. Perruquetti, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Estimation and Control of Discrete-Time LPV
Systems Using Interval Observers&lt;/em&gt;, 52nd IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, December 10-13,
2013, Florence, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;S. Chebotarev, D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;On Interval Observer Design for a Class of
Continuous-Time LPV Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 9th IFAC Symposium on Nonlinear Control Systems, (NOLCOS’2013),
Toulouse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Stanislav Chebotarev, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;On Set-Membership Observer Design for
a Class of Nonlinear Time-Varying Systems&lt;/em&gt;, CDC’2012, Maui, Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R. Seydou, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, D. Efimov, C. Combastel, &lt;em&gt;Robust Fault Diagnosis with Interval
Continuous-time Parity Equations&lt;/em&gt;, Fault Detection, 8th IFAC Symposium On Fault Detection,
Supervision and Safety for Technical Processes (Safeprocess’2012), Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;H. Rios, D. Efimov, J. Davila, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, L. Fridman, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;State Estimation and Fault
Detection for Linear Switched Systems with Unstable Internal Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;, 8th IFAC Symposium On
Fault Detection, Supervision and Safety for Technical Processes (Safeprocess’2012), Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, L. Fridman, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, R. Seydou, &lt;em&gt;Application of Interval Observers and
HOSM Differentiators for Fault Detection&lt;/em&gt;, 8th IFAC Symposium On Fault Detection, Supervision and
Safety for Technical Processes (Safeprocess’2012), Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;H. Rios, D. Efimov, J. Davila, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, L. Fridman, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;State Estimation for Linear
Switched Systems with Unknown Inputs&lt;/em&gt;, 4th IFAC conference on Analysis and Design of Hybrid
Systems (ADHS’2012), June 6-8, 2012, Eindhoven, The Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R. Seydou, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, D. Henry, &lt;em&gt;Change detection in flat systems by constraint satisfaction
techniques&lt;/em&gt;, IFAC-WC’2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Robust fault detection based on adaptive set observers&lt;/em&gt;, SysTol’10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Monotone adaptive set observers for nonlinear continuous-time
systems&lt;/em&gt;, NOLCOS’10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, D. Efimov, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Robust state and parameter estimation for nonlinear continuoustime
systems. Application to fault detection&lt;/em&gt;, 16th European Conference on Mathematics for Industry
2010, ECMI’2010.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Videau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Set-observer design for consistency checks of nonlinear systems&lt;/em&gt;,
SAFEPROCESS’09, July 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Robust nonlinear continuous-time state estimation using interval
Taylor models&lt;/em&gt;, invited session, ROCOND’06.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;articles-réguliers:b12bb71970583c53de3daa7003b0cb29&#34;&gt;Articles réguliers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;B. Yousfi, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, M. Amairi and M. Aoun, &lt;em&gt;Interval Observers Design for Singularly Perturbed Systems&lt;/em&gt;,
53rd IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, December 15-17, 2014. Los Angeles, California,
USA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Gucik-Derigny, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Interval State and Unknown Inputs Estimation for Linear
Time-Invariant Systems&lt;/em&gt;, IFAC-WC’2014, August 24-29, 2014, Cape Town, South Africa, Strasbourg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R.H. Thabet, C. Combastel, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Set-membership fault detection under noisy
environment in aircraft control surface servo-loops&lt;/em&gt;, IFAC-WC’2014, August 24-29, 2014, Cape Town,
South Africa, Strasbourg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R.H. Thabet, C. Combastel, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Computing Reachable Sets For
Nonlinear Systems In Presence Of Bounded Uncertainties&lt;/em&gt;, European Control Conference, (ECC’2014),
Strasbourg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R.H. Thabet, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, C. Combastel, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Interval Observers Design for LPV systems with
additive disturbances, European Control Conference&lt;/em&gt;, (ECC’2013), Zurich, Suisse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, W. Perruquetti, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;On Interval Observer Design for Time-Invariant
Discrete-Time Systems, European Control Conference&lt;/em&gt;, (ECC’2013), Zurich, Suisse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, L. Fridman, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, R. Seydou, &lt;em&gt;Set-Membership Estimation Improvement
Applying HOSM Differentiators&lt;/em&gt;, ACC’2012, Montreal, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Stabilization of nonlinear uncertain systems based on interval
observers&lt;/em&gt;, CDC-ECC’2011, Orlando, FL, USA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, D. Efimov, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Reliable amplitude and frequency estimation for biased and noisy
signals - Application to oscillatory failures detection&lt;/em&gt;, European Conference for AeroSpace Sciences,
EUCASS’2011, Saint-Petersburg, Russia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R. Seydou, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri,_ Robust State Estimation for Flat Systems Using Set-Membership
Techniques_, IFAC-WC’2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, A. Zolghadri, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hybrid unknown input observer for actuator fault detection and
compensation&lt;/em&gt;, IFAC-WC’2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R. Seydou, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, D. Henry, &lt;em&gt;Fault detection in flat systems by constraint satisfaction
and input monitoring&lt;/em&gt;, ACD’10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;D. Efimov, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Adaptive Set Observers Design For Fault Detection And Diagnosis&lt;/em&gt;,
MED’10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Videau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Tests de cohérence pour des systèmes non linéaires à temps continu
par observateurs intervalles&lt;/em&gt;, CIFA’10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;F. Khemane, R. Malti, X. Moreau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, M. Thomassin, &lt;em&gt;Comparison between two set membership
methods for frequency domain system identification using fractional models&lt;/em&gt;, ACC’10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Videau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Guaranteed state estimation for nonlinear continuous-time systems
based on qLPV transformations&lt;/em&gt;, ECC’09, August 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R. Malti, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, M. Thomassin, F. Khemane, &lt;em&gt;Parameter estimation of fractional models&lt;/em&gt;, FDA2008,
Novembre 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Videau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Contrôle de cohérence paramétrique des systèmes non linéaires à
temps continu par satisfaction de contraintes&lt;/em&gt;, CIFA 2008, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;sélectionné meilleur article théorique&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;F. Khemane, R. Malti, M. Thomassin, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Set membership estimation of fractional models in
the frequency domain&lt;/em&gt;, 17th IFAC World Congress, Seoul, July 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Videau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Set membership state estimation for nonlinear systems using
contraction theory&lt;/em&gt;, 17th IFAC World Congress, Seoul, July 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Videau, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. Zolghadri, &lt;em&gt;Détection de défauts par analyse par intervalles, Journées Identification
et Modélisation Expérimentale&lt;/em&gt;, Poitiers, 16-17 novembre 2006.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;N. Meslem, N. Ramdani &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Estimation des paramètres des systèmes à temps
continu par une approche ensembliste&lt;/em&gt;, CIFA 2006, Bordeaux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;N. Ramdani, N. Meslem, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Set-membership identification of continuous-time
systems&lt;/em&gt;, SYSID’06, pp.446-451.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;N. Ramdani, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Candau, L. Ibos, &lt;em&gt;Complex interval constraint propagation for non linear
bounded-error parameter identification&lt;/em&gt;, CDC-ECC’05.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, L. Ibos, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Guaranteed method for the estimation of dielectric relaxation
models parameters&lt;/em&gt;, 5th International Conference on Inverse Problems in Engineering: Theory
and Practice, Cambridge, 2005.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;N. Ramdani, &lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Candau, L. Ibos, A. Boudenne, &lt;em&gt;Set membership parameter identification
with complex intervals using polar form&lt;/em&gt;, 16th IFAC World Congress, Prague. July 2005.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, L. Ibos, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Guaranteed method for the estimation of dielectric
relaxation models parameters&lt;/em&gt;, 8th IEEE International Conference on Solid Dielectrics, ICSD2004,
Toulouse, pp. 111-114, Juillet 2004.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, L. Ibos, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Analyse de spectres de relaxation diélectrique par
arithmétique d’intervalles&lt;/em&gt;, 4ème Conférence Européenne sur les méthodes numériques en électromagnétisme,
NUMELEC2003, Toulouse, Octobre 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Parameter estimation for non-linear continuous-time systems
in a bounded error context&lt;/em&gt;, 42nd IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, CDC2003, Hawaii, pp.
2240-2245, December 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;State estimation for non-linear continuous systems in a bounded
error context&lt;/em&gt;, 13th IFAC Symposium on System Identification, SYSID2003, Rotterdam, pp. 1725-1730,
August 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, N. Ramdani, Y. Candau, &lt;em&gt;Estimation d’état pour des systèmes décrits par des équations
différentielles non linéaires dans un contexte à erreurs bornées&lt;/em&gt;, Journées Doctorales d’automatique,
JDA2003, Valenciennes, Juin 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T. Raïssi&lt;/strong&gt;, A. El Kamel, W. Byrski, P. Borne, &lt;em&gt;Multimodel analysis and control of multivariable Systems,
IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man and Cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;, IEEE/SMC’01, Tucson, pp.
640-645, October 2001.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prix &amp; responsabilités</title>
      <link>/prix-resp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/prix-resp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt;   Titulaire de la &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prime d’Excellence Scientifique depuis 2013&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt;   Prix du &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;meilleur article théorique CIFA 2008&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; avec G. Videau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt;   Prix de la &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meilleure Thèse d’Automatique 2003-2005&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; du GDR MACS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt;   Prix du &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;meilleur article de session&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, American Control Conference, ACC’2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre du comité technique d’IFAC TC 1.1 &amp;ldquo;Modeling, Identification and Signal Processing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre de &amp;ldquo;Action Group on Interval Methods, IEEE Technical Committee on Computational Aspects of Control System Design&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre sénior IEEE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-organisateur (avec Vicenç Puig &amp;amp; Christophe Combastel) du numéro spécial &amp;ldquo;Set-membership Methods Applied to FDI and FTC&amp;rdquo; à paraître dans la revue &amp;ldquo;International Journal of Adaptive Control and Signal Processing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre du comité éditorial des revues &amp;ldquo;American Journal of Applied Mathematics&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;American Journal of Aerospace Engineering&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre du comité national d’organisation de la conférence &amp;ldquo;IFAC Symposium on Fault Detection, Supervision and Safety of Technical Processes - 9th SAFEPROCESS 2015&amp;rdquo;, Paris&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre du comité d’organisation de la conférence &amp;ldquo;International Conference on Systems, Analysis and Automatic Control&amp;rdquo;, Barcelone, 2014&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre du comité d’organisation du &amp;ldquo;6th International Workshop on Verification and Evaluation of Computer and Communication Systems&amp;rdquo;, Paris, 2012&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Editeur associé pour la conférence 8th IFAC Symposium on Nonlinear Control Systems (NOLCOS’2010), Bologne, Italie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisateur de la session invitée &amp;ldquo;Set-membership state and parameter estimation for nonlinear systems&amp;rdquo;, 8th IFAC Symposium on Nonlinear Control Systems (NOLCOS’2010), Bologne, Italie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisateur de la session invitée &amp;ldquo;Fault Detection and Isolation based on set-membership techniques&amp;rdquo;, 7th IFAC Symposium on Fault Detection, Supervision and Safety of Technical Processes (SAFEPROCESS’2009), Barcelone, Espagne&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-organisateur de la session invitée &amp;ldquo;Robust diagnosis based on set-membership techniques&amp;rdquo;, 18th IFAC World Congress Milan, Italie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-organisateur de la session invitée &amp;ldquo;Robust estimation of uncertain systems&amp;rdquo;, 51st IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, Maui, Hawaii, 2012&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-organisateur de la session invitée &amp;ldquo;Interval estimation of uncertain systems&amp;rdquo;, 52nd IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, Florence, Italie, 2013&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-organisateur de la session invitée &amp;ldquo;Set-membership-based techniques for robust diagnosis - I&amp;rdquo; 7th IFAC Symposium on Fault Detection, Supervision and Safety of Technical Processes (SAFEPROCESS’2015), Paris, France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-organisateur de la session invitée &amp;ldquo;Set-membership-based techniques for robust diagnosis - II&amp;rdquo; 7th IFAC Symposium on Fault Detection, Supervision and Safety of Technical Processes (SAFEPROCESS’2015), Paris, France&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-président de la session &amp;ldquo;Robust diagnosis based on set-membership techniques&amp;rdquo;, 18th IFAC World Congress Milan, Italie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Président de la session &amp;ldquo;Set-membership state and parameter estimation for nonlinear systems&amp;rdquo;, 8th IFAC Symposium on Nonlinear Control Systems, Bologna, Italy, 2010&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Président de la session &amp;ldquo;Nonlinear Systems I&amp;rdquo;, European Control Conference, Budapest, Hongrie, 2009&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Président de la session &amp;ldquo;Fault Detection and Isolation based on set-membership techniques&amp;rdquo;, SAFEPROCESS’2009, Barcelone, Espagne&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expert pour l’école doctorale de &amp;ldquo;Polytechnic University of Catalonia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evaluateur pour la plupart des revues de référence en Automatique : Automatica, IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control, Annual Reviews of Control, European Journal of Control, International Journal of Adaptive Control and Signal Processing, Signal Processing, International Journal of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, International Journal of Modelling, Identification and Control, Circuits Systems and Signal Processing, International Journal of Control, Journal of Process Control, JESA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre du Conseil du Laboratoire Cedric du Cnam&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responsable du Mastère spécialisé (label de la Conférence des Grandes Ecoles) &amp;ldquo;Systèmes Mécatroniques et Robotiques&amp;rdquo;, Cnam&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responsable du diplôme d’ingénieur Génie Industriel, Cnam&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre du Conseil du département Génie Electrique et Informatique Industrielle de l’IUT Bordeaux 1, 2008-2011&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Directeur des études au département Génie Electrique et Informatique Industrielle de l’IUT Bordeaux 1, 2007-2009&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre d’un comité de sélection pour le recrutement d’un MCF en 61ème section, Université de Bordeaux : 61 MCF 550 (2015)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre d’un comité de sélection pour le recrutement d’un MCF en 61ème section, UHP, Nancy. Poste: 61-MCF-0040 (2012)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre d’un comité de sélection pour le recrutement d’un MCF en 61ème section, UHP, Nancy. Poste: 61-MCF-0213 (2011)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membre d’un comité de sélection pour le recrutement d’un MCF en 61-63 èmes sections, IPB. Poste: 6163-MCF-0134 (2011)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enseignement</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 14:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt; Commande des systèmes linéaires&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt; commande des systèmes à temps discret&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt; Commande temps réel - systèmes multi-tâches&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt; Programmation des robots industriels&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-hand-right&#34;/&gt; Programmation des micro-contrôleurs&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>